Every moment is another chance.
8 Mile is a drama, music film directed by Curtis Hanson.
For Jimmy Smith, Jr., life is a daily fight just to keep hope alive.
Feeding his dreams in Detroit's vibrant music scene, Jimmy wages an extraordinary personal struggle to find his own voice
- and earn a place in a world where rhymes rule, legends are born and every moment… is another chance.
Jimmy, played by Eminem.
Stephanie, played by Kim Basinger.
Future, played by Mekhi Phifer.
Alex, played by Brittany Murphy.
Cheddar Bob, played by Evan Jones.
Sol George, played by Omar Benson Miller.
8 Mile is a 2002 hip-hop biographical drama film produced and directed
by Curtis Hanson from a script written by Scott Silver.
It stars Eminem in his film debut, alongside Mekhi Phifer, Brittany Murphy, Michael
Shannon, Kim Basinger and Anthony Mackie, the latter also in his film debut.
The film, which contains autobiographical elements from
Eminem's life, follows Detroit rapper Jimmy Smith Jr.
aka B-Rabbit (Eminem) and his attempt to launch a career in
hip-hop, a music genre dominated by African Americans.
The title is derived from 8 Mile Road, the road between the predominantly black city of Detroit and
the largely white suburban communities to the north that Eminem originally lived in.
8 Mile was released by Universal Pictures on November 8, 2002 in
the United States and January 2, 2003 in Germany.
The film was a critical and commercial success.
It opened at No.
1 in the US with $51.3 million grossed in its opening weekend and
an eventual total of $242.9 million worldwide.
The film's accompanying soundtrack (released by Universal's then subsidiary Universal Music, through Interscope and Shady/Aftermath) was
also a commercial success, being certified quadruple platinum by the Recording Industry Association of America (RIAA).
The film received generally positive reviews, praising the music and
performances, though some noted its unoriginality.
The film garnered numerous award nominations and wins, including an Academy Award for Best Original Song
win for "Lose Yourself" for Eminem, Jeff Bass and Luis Resto at the 75th Academy Awards.
8 Mile was named one of the best films of 2002 by several publications.
The film explores themes of individual, adolescence,
rap music, hip-hop, rhyme battle.
The tone is emotional.